I Pastor Life Church International imor
and also as you have begun we began with
truth mentorship
society which is a body that does
interor meting with the hung of Revival
Upon Our
Generation so let me dive straight to
the topic of the day I have three object
Ives how to enter in a Godly
relationship how to cultivate a Godly
relationship Ms and
misconceptions about
marriage and I want to talk
about love made in
Eden back to the original
design let us look at Genesis chapter
number 2 and verse
15 when you're talking relationships
nobody Sleeps so this is a good
topic Genesis
2:15 let us build it from scripture
Hallelujah the Lord God took the
man and put him in the Garden of Eden to
work it
a care of it so the Lord took the man
who was this man that the Lord
took let us go to Genesis chapter number
one from verse
25 let us understand this
man this thing will be deep because
relationship is not about
feelings God made the wild animals
according to their their kind are you
seeing that name
kind the livestock according to their
kind and the creatures that move along
the ground according to their kind and
God so that it was good the Hebrew word
there is
functional so animals were made
according to their
kind but in Genesis
1:26 then God said let us make man the
the original rendering is not man it is
mankind remember he made animals
according to their
kind but now he is making a man
kind now let's get this right that man
is not
male it is a kind that is
man now God said let us make a kind that
is
man so God was making a kind of God that
man okay I said it's going to be
deep I have not five keys of a
functional relationship I have
scripture are we together so this man is
a
kind of God in human form can we journey
further the Earth is a tabernacle or a
sanctuary that's what the Earth is it's
a tabernacle or a
s and the reason why the Bible ends with
a new Earth and a new Heaven is because
when sin entered the sanctuary was
defiled are we
together when you go to cultures of
deities or Gods when people have
sanctuaries for their
gods they put
images of their gods in the
sanctuaries now this is a sanctuary of
God and God placed his image in this
sanctuary and that's you and
me so this man you can see let us plural
because the Hebrew version of talking
about a big person was plural so if
Bishop is great in our day we cannot
refer him to him we will refer him to
them are we
together in our likeness let's make man
in our
image that is
projection not
reflection my daughter I have an amazing
daughter when she was growing up people
are
saying If Today Was to deny my my
daughter my wife will laugh and just a
DNA and they will take a sample of a
saliva saliva and they will discover
there are elements in me that are in
her so when God was saying let us let
them bear our image it means there are
things in us that they
carry
okay and likeness that is
automatically because they are our
nature is in them they will behave like
us now God made man the second part of
this scripture is for
intercessors
hello that second part is for
intercessors because it shows the three
spheres of rulership
hydrosphere lithosphere and
atmosphere okay I'm a geologist by
training that is gxc form
2 hydrosphere is water bodies Marine
power lithosphere is land land power and
atmosphere is powers that rule the
heavens and the air sell we here for
relationships let's go to the next next
one now let's
read the most
complicated verse that does not obey
grammatical order in the
Bible because this verse cannot be
accurate in English because it speaks
spiritual
realities God created man
singular in his own image singular in
the image of God he created him singular
male and female he created them
plural that verse breaks the sequence of
grammar how does a singular
entity change to be plural in the same
statement now forget biology and forget
English and come to
theology when you hear a male you think
a
man when you hear a female you think a
woman because of sexual
organs the the name male in the Bible
has nothing to do with a man according
to what we
Define
okay the name female has nothing to do
with the
woman you see the holy spirit is always
called
paracletus in
Greek the holy spirit is given a
feminine
Dimension but the Holy Spirit does not
have
gender because God does not have gender
so what does this mean God created man
that male means
Authority and that female means
power so there was one remember this is
a kind of God
so in this kind he has put Authority and
power wrapped up in one
order are we together are we together up
to
there so this man singular had the
ability to demonstrate the authority and
power of
God now remember this man for him to
carry these dual Dimensions he existed
as a
spirit this one of Genesis was not flesh
this one was a
spirit that's why he had the ability to
exist as Authority and power this was
not an
amrite that's why I said forget biology
and
Medicine are we
there now can I confirm to you that this
man was a
spirit Genesis
27 Genesis
2:7 love not 277 that's your message sir
mine is
27 you're doing well but even there we
could get a message but let's stick to
the
theme everybody
read okay begin from five begin from
five so that we can know begin from
five
uh-huh now listen where was the man of
Genesis 1
that man was a spirit Spirits don't hold
gers Spirits cannot work on the so we
can see the operation of the world was
suspended because there was no man
physically now this begins to open our
eyes that you are
as that lives in a
body and your assignment is not in the
body your body gives you legal ground of
operation on
Earth and that order must be like so the
reason why many relationships fail is
because people bring their bodies and
not their
Spirits so you take two hours on the
mirror applying
foundation working on the eyelashes
makeup looking for the tightest and the
fitting
vessels making sure that all you bring
on that table is flesh and
blood and the man takes time to look for
his muscle
shut and don't touch and load his
wallet so these two people have met on a
caral level
that relationship will end up in bed not
on the altar because what they brought
was their bodies and the lady will begin
to ask why is it that all men are after
my body but what did you
bring why is it that all women after my
money but what did you show
me and that's the first error there is a
lot of body
encounters the order of man is Spirit
soul
body that's why when you mature in the
spirit you never marry because of body
size and shape you marry because of
spirit size and
[Applause]
shape if you are still on how what is a
color skin
biceps beard gun you still have some
growing to
do because a man can have beards but
with the brain of a
child
Hallelujah
so the Lord said sins there was no man
to deal the land the Lord now
formed now that is s the Lord formed the
man of the Dust so there was a man that
God
created and there was a man that God
form the assignment of man was not in
the form the assignment of man was on
the cre created being the
spirit therefore this body gives me
legal ground to operate on Earth that's
the role of this body legality on Earth
but all my assignments are in the spirit
I cannot Know Myself according to the
body that's why Paul writes and says now
we know no man after the flesh because
you are a spirit wrapped up with
Earth and for those that have stayed in
marriage and we look at the
misconception they will tell you after
two years you get used to the
beauty after two years you get used to
the
biceps and you begin to look for
something greater than
appearance it's the same thing I give
you a Range Rover today after two
months the excitement will not be
there and the reason why many marriages
are not working is because people marry
for the wrong
reasons and the reason why many people
are not even staying in relationships is
because the pattern has been disrupted
we are using the secular pattern to run
Kingdom
relationships and it can't work so the
Lord God formed the man of the and
breathed in him and became a living
being or or a living
soul that man was both male and female
in
Eden he had Authority
and
power now we were looking for the man
that God
took that is the man
okay and his name was not
Adam the problem with this man he named
everything except
himself he said your name shall be Eve
the mother of all
creation when the Lord was calling in
Eden after the fall he said Adam Adam
where are you we are coming to that
question
that name Adam means from the
clay so that is not a name it is a
source
okay now let's go to 15 15 is where we
begin to get
answers Hallelujah I I dated I dated
until I got tired until this scripture
came into my
spirit I I I was had broken
relationships failed
successfully and as I continue to grow I
discovered that there are people God
brings in our lives for
discipleship but we decided to enter
courtship and when the program of
discipleship is over the Lord takes them
out of the class and the Lord hands them
over to their right
owner that is how you date a man or a
woman for 4 years you teach them prayer
teach them the word of God and you
prepare them and by the time they become
a wife someone marries them let let me
help
[Applause]
you let me help
you the Lord brought her or him for
discipleship but your appetites
introduce other
agendas and if you have ever found
yourself in such a situation let me
encourage you
during the wedding ceremony please sit
where pastoral team sits
because you pasted that
person don't pray for thunder and rain
during their wedding stand where a
pastor stand and say that's my spiritual
son that
[Applause]
one Hallelujah or your spiritual
daughter and bless the Lord for the good
work you've
done the Lord God took the man and put
him and put him in the Garden of Eden to
walk it and take care of
it that name Eden means in the presence
of
God the first place God took man was in
his presence
and then in the presence there is the
purpose of
God so you if you need a wife or a
husband show up in the
presence show up in the
presence in the book of
Corinthians the Bible says what does
light have to do with Darkness
and it talks about being
yoked with
bellal that is a
demon of lessness and
rowdiness according to God an
nonbeliever is in the level of a demon
called
Bal I know we we we simplify this
thing now what happens when he talks
about don't be unequally
y a y was designed for animals of the
species you can never place a donkey
where a bull is supposed to show up with
its head because
even those who are designing the York
they design it for Bulls animals of the
same
species the Yoke of marriage is designed
for people of the same species born
again the moment you put a
horse and a camel in the same York one
will bear more wheat and it is
tiresome that's why you must interrogate
the
species and don't look for a
God-fearing man even the devil is
[Music]
godfy look for a God loving man or
woman
those are the
standards so the first thing was
presence and the second one was
purpose Pastor how do I know if she's
the one or he's the one very simple what
is your purpose your purpose is the
elimination
method when I knew God has called me to
Ministry so many many potential ladies
were
eliminated some were good in business I
knew they can fit in this assignment
because God called me for Souls not
sales some were prophesying
vibrating I also knew they are not the
ones not because I was not looking for a
prayerful woman it's because I was
looking for a woman we can grow together
in the
God and in my Heart of heart I was
looking for a woman that I can raise in
the
Lord because some of them don't submit
because when there is chaos they begin
to say yesterday I had a vision and I
sense the
devil is attacking
us so I was looking at one that we were
almost in the same level spiritually
because sometimes you get a person who
is very high and they use their position
to manipulate
you and tell you yesterday the Lord told
me the the point is you are flatting
with another
woman you need to
apologize you don't begin to wake up and
say as I was flatting there are things
God was
revealing are you getting me so that
level of balance was needed and everyone
had a wife that I needed to
marry even you there are people who feel
you need to be married by so and
so there is no Matchmaker even
pastors it is a
choice we can have desires have you ever
realized some of the perfect couples
don't go
far and some of the people we look like
their mother
thanel they are the ones who
last
yes some of these perfect they don't
last because God is the best
Matchmaker no man even we
pastors we can advice but we cannot
decide because God knows your destiny
like I'll tell you I led my wife to the
Lord I baptized her discipled her
married her and I'm pastoring
her now it's not that I went to look for
an unbeliever
no when we met I discovered she was not
born again I told the Lord I know your
standards and at least I know I don't
know who to marry but I know these were
no until there's a green light then she
began to come to Fellowship then I
discovered she came from a Muslim
background and she was not permitted to
go to church so it was not her fault she
had not heard the gospel so one day she
came heard the gospel I was preaching
and said I want to give my life to Jesus
I led her to to Jesus she attended
discipleship class it was so good she
repeated and now I began to locate her
heart I said this one is a good
one my most romantic
moment was not any dinner that we took
is when I saw my wife coming in the
baptism pool do you know why there was
no makeup I saw the real
woman
hallelujah it's good to attend
baptisms and I saw her I said Lord this
is a good
thing
and we got
married we did not date for 5 years it
was not a
presidential
[Applause]
time two years was
enough one year to interrogate one
another and the second year to plan the
wedding there's a level of maturity that
you reach and you know what you
want and you are specific and you have
your n
negotiables values it had nothing to do
with appearance values your heart
attitude some things were nonnegotiable
and we met on a ground I used to live
with my young sister because I couldn't
trust myself with my
freedom yeah some of you live alone and
that is the door of all your
mistakes you need someone that can
disrupt your
singlehood and so my young sister was
there and I told her if any any lady
ever comes in this house and stays past
news
news one to remind me that I'm a pastor
and there is a woman in that house past
her
hours two weeks to the wedding are the
most tempting weeks you can abstain for
two years you get closer you begin now
get attractive
and I remember one day my wife stayed in
my house until 11: we're planning for
the wedding my sister was there and I
remember dropping and she gave me a
lecture and told me how many people will
understand she's your fiance 11 what
were you doing with a woman in a car
alone and her how
many I told her I have failed as your
pastor forgive me my sister
it will never happen at least I was sure
there are around 10
days and I knew it will never happen
because someone was about to
board that time she was a discolor
amen hallelujah don't make her board
without boarding
certificates
yes are you seeing that let's continue
reading and the Lord God commanded the
man you are free to eat from any tree in
the garden it was a
command
continue but you must not eat from the
Tree of knowledge of Good and Evil for
when you eat of it you will surely die
continue everybody
read hold it there was it the opinion of
some Elders in the village
Village who kept on
asking was it the pressure in a WhatsApp
group has the Lord Sav over your
life God looked at man and said it is
not
good for man to be
alone grammar is very
good it was not
lonely this has nothing to do with
emotions it was alone
numerical many people did because they
are
lonely God remember man had a
relationship with
God I know you have a relationship with
Christ but he's not your boyfriend
you need someone in your
real God is is a spirit in another
real and you need someone of your
species that is not your
species
bab that is your
species you need a man in your real a
man or a woman not a
spirit intercessors are we
together you need a person in your real
human
damn but God must say it is not
good when was God saying it is not good
when man was in
Eden doing the work of God it is called
purpose now what was God doing he never
said oh man is alone he needs a lover
that is not the language the language is
man needs a helper
God never created marriage For
Love by the way one of the deceptions
about marriage is that people marry
because of
Love
hey it is a
lie and and I'll take you through Bible
and it is women who love men it is not
your all I don't know who you who told
you to love
men
okay Ephesians 5:21 and 22 let's see who
needs to love
who Ephesians
5 21 and
22 Ephesians
ores everybody
read
uhhuh
hold it there what are you doing washing
your boyfriend
dishes the Bible says wives not
girlfriends does the Bible say
love it
says submit to
your as
unto what does that word mean that name
submit is military it is a language of
rank meaning that you can be a PhD
holder married to a form four liever but
you know according to rank he's above
[Music]
[Applause]
me because God is not an author of
confusion this word submit is borrowed
from Greek military words you know I had
Bishop is darari he knows that in New
Testament some words were Borrowed by so
that he can explain some truth of the
Gospel especially when he was talking to
Greeks and people that were under the
Greek culture so when they read this
they knew as a woman when you look at
your husband you don't submit because he
has
money you don't submit because he's
wealthy you don't submit MIT because he
has status you submit because in that
house God has given him a rank called
husband in the
military there are people who are more
masculine than the
commander some are more educated than
the commander but the orders of a
commander are
LA and they submit because they honor
the rank but the Bible does not leave it
unto foolish submission because you're
not a punching b as unto the Lord
meaning that if this submission is not
according to the word of God you have
the right not to I'll give you a very
practical example my wife has worked in
the insurance for 10 years and this time
she was working in a senior position and
I gave one of my pastors the car and he
didn't have a driving license so he
drove as he was reversing he was going
for
Mission and he came he said we are sorry
n so we waited for my wife so he said
hey baby you're good you know we have a
small accident she said what uh the
William was driving the
car and then we said since you work in
the insurance so she write a report and
said you're the one who was driving to
Mission do you know what she told me I
cannot
[Applause]
lie I almost became spiritual I said you
know even Adam Abraham
lied for security
purpose and was she rebellious no
whatever we were requesting was not as
unto the Lord
God so she stood the first relationship
is her relationship with
God are we together and that's why if
you are married to a man that is of not
the same species you will struggle
imagine a man coming with cultural
mindset
even in my
coffee it's a
burden that's why this understanding has
to be there am I speaking to
anyone so women the language is not
manipulation and
abuse uh it is so that means if all of
us are born again we subscribe to one
order I know what to do and she knows
what to do if it's not of the
Lord she has no authority to submit can
I even go further
yes a lady came and told me
py I'm afraid I asked her
why she told me my relationship is
sexual told her leave she said but I
don't want to hurt him I said
okay I said now here you have a
relationship with
Jesus and a relationship with
Jon Jesus wants you to walk pure if you
don't walk pure you hurt
Jesus J Mo wants sex if you don't give J
Mo sex you hurt J Mo who is better to
hurt now I said I said
listen J can never give you Jesus but
Jesus can give you another
J so I say choose who you want to
lose because someone will be hurt at the
end of the
day B
you
so the language here is submit and this
one will begin to address the question
of meats and misconception of marriage
is that we don't marry for love we marry
for
purpose we don't marry for we marry for
purpose and when we are so much in tune
in purpose automatically we we will be
connected
emotionally and I come to that
ofes now go to
23 go to 23 I want to show you how we
have missed everybody
read do you know why Paul is using this
example because I tell you the truth
we are more concerned about the welfare
of the
body more than the
head so a Godly husband will take care
of his
body and it is not by force manipulation
cassion you will take care of your body
that's your your
wife it is your responsibility to feed
her clothe her and take care of
her
Hallelujah there are times I always tell
my wife come and damage my
wallet right now she's
[Applause]
pregnant
Miss I tell you I'll have to look for it
whether I have Mone because you take
care how do you take care of it you take
care of it well now see what men are
given to do
24 everybody
read
H
25 hold it there
husbands if you're sitting next to a
woman just ask
her we are going back to the
Bible husbands do what love
your